<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Truelog</title>
	<atom:link href="https://truelog.com.sg/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://truelog.com.sg/</link>
	<description>TrueLog offers comprehensive logistics solutions, from freight forwarding to IT logistics, ensuring efficiency and reliability.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 12:14:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://truelog.com.sg/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/cropped-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Truelog</title>
	<link>https://truelog.com.sg/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Truelog Launches IOR &#038; EOR Services into La Réunion</title>
		<link>https://truelog.com.sg/truelog-launches-ior-eor-services-into-la-reunion/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[TrueLog3]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 12:14:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://truelog.com.sg/?p=56853</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>La Réunion: Strategic Island for ICT GrowthLocated in the Indian Ocean and administratively part of France, La Réunion is evolving into a regional digital and technology hub. With increasing investment in cloud, fibre, and telecom infrastructure, the island is undergoing a quiet transformation to support next-generation connectivity. The French government and EU-backed initiatives continue to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/truelog-launches-ior-eor-services-into-la-reunion/">Truelog Launches IOR &amp; EOR Services into La Réunion</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>La Réunion: Strategic Island for ICT Growth<br>Located in the Indian Ocean and administratively part of France, La Réunion is evolving into a regional digital and technology hub. With increasing investment in cloud, fibre, and telecom infrastructure, the island is undergoing a quiet transformation to support next-generation connectivity.</p>



<p>The French government and EU-backed initiatives continue to fund major digital upgrades, including subsea fibre connectivity and local cloud data centres, paving the way for future-ready telecom and datacentre expansion.</p>



<p>Growing Demand for ICT Infrastructure</p>



<p>La Réunion’s small size belies its growing role in the Indian Ocean tech ecosystem. As African and APAC trade routes diversify, the island is becoming a key node for connectivity, backup infrastructure, and cloud‑based platforms.</p>



<p>With this growth comes increased demand for:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Telecom equipment<br></li>



<li>Networking hardware<br></li>



<li>Secure datacentre infrastructure<br></li>



<li>Smart city and IoT systems<br></li>
</ul>



<p>Importing ICT Goods into La Réunion: Key Considerations</p>



<p>Although part of France and the EU, La Réunion is an outermost region (OMR), which means logistics and customs processes differ from mainland France or Europe.</p>



<p>Required Documentation</p>



<p>To import IT and telecom hardware into La Réunion, clients must prepare:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Commercial invoice &amp; packing list<br></li>



<li>Certificate of origin<br></li>



<li>CE Marking &amp; Declaration of Conformity for ICT goods<br></li>



<li>Any applicable French telecom import permits<br></li>
</ul>



<p>Duties and Taxes</p>



<p>Goods shipped to La Réunion are subject to:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Octroi de Mer (dock entry tax): ~5–20% depending on product classification<br></li>



<li>VAT (TVA): applicable at a localised rate<br></li>



<li>Import duties for goods originating outside the EU<br></li>
</ul>



<p>Correct classification and documentation are essential to avoid customs delays, overpayment, or rejections.</p>



<p>Truelog’s Expertise in La Réunion</p>



<p>Truelog now provides full Importer and Exporter of Record (IOR/EOR) services into La Réunion, ensuring ICT deployments are smooth, compliant, and efficient.</p>



<p>With our services, clients benefit from:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>End-to-end customs clearance<br></li>



<li>Local tax and duty compliance<br></li>



<li>Accurate documentation and telecom certifications<br></li>



<li>White glove delivery options for sensitive hardware<br></li>



<li>Live visibility dashboards and full shipment traceability<br></li>
</ul>



<p>As demand for IT infrastructure expands into island territories like La Réunion, navigating complex import regulations becomes critical. Truelog is here to make it seamless.</p>



<p>Planning your next deployment in La Réunion?<br>Get in touch with our IOR/EOR team today at sales@truelog.com.sg.</p>



<p>#ICTlogistics #IORservices #LaReunion #TelecomSupplyChain #EMEAlogistics</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/truelog-launches-ior-eor-services-into-la-reunion/">Truelog Launches IOR &amp; EOR Services into La Réunion</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Navigating U.S. Tariff Volatility: What ICT Logistics Leaders Need to Know</title>
		<link>https://truelog.com.sg/navigating-u-s-tariff-volatility-what-ict-logistics-leaders-need-to-know/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[TrueLog3]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 12:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://truelog.com.sg/?p=56850</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In late July 2025, the U.S. government announced sweeping measures aimed at curbing tariff evasion via transshipment. These rules introduce complex two-tier tariff systems and stricter rules of origin, set to take effect on 1 August 2025. For global telecom, datacentre, and cloud infrastructure providers, these regulatory shifts create immediate supply chain challenges. The Impact: [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/navigating-u-s-tariff-volatility-what-ict-logistics-leaders-need-to-know/">Navigating U.S. Tariff Volatility: What ICT Logistics Leaders Need to Know</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In late July 2025, the U.S. government announced sweeping measures aimed at curbing tariff evasion via transshipment. These rules introduce complex two-tier tariff systems and stricter rules of origin, set to take effect on <strong>1 August 2025</strong>. For global telecom, datacentre, and cloud infrastructure providers, these regulatory shifts create immediate supply chain challenges.</p>



<p>The Impact: Increased Complexity and Cost</p>



<p>The new policy framework affects companies that:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Source components from multiple jurisdictions<br></li>



<li>Route shipments through free trade zones or indirect markets<br></li>



<li>Rely on split shipments or multi-country assembly lines<br></li>
</ul>



<p>Coupled with continued tariff volatility, highlighted in the <strong>July 2025 ITS Logistics report</strong>, these developments raise critical questions around <strong>customs compliance</strong>, <strong>cost predictability</strong>, and <strong>supply chain risk</strong>.</p>



<p>Risks for ICT Supply Chains</p>



<p>For the ICT sector, the risks are pronounced:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Margin pressure</strong> due to unexpected duties or misclassification<br></li>



<li><strong>Customs delays</strong> from incorrect origin declarations<br></li>



<li><strong>Penalties or audits</strong> tied to transshipment inconsistencies<br></li>



<li><strong>Hardware deployment bottlenecks</strong> in key regions<br></li>
</ul>



<p>These issues hit especially hard in projects where hardware delivery timelines and SLA fulfilment are mission-critical—such as datacentre builds or telecom expansions.</p>



<p>How Truelog Helps Navigate Tariff and Transshipment Risks</p>



<p>At Truelog, we specialise in helping clients mitigate customs and compliance risks with a logistics model built on <strong>clarity, control, and compliance</strong>:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Global IOR/EOR Services</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>We act as your Importer or Exporter of Record in over 120 countries, ensuring customs documentation is accurate and compliant with evolving trade laws.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Real-Time Tariff Intelligence</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>We actively monitor and update our internal tariff databases to reflect the latest policy changes—helping clients avoid surprises and plan shipments with confidence.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Risk-Aware Route Planning</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>We proactively design routing strategies to avoid transshipment red flags, choosing paths that balance efficiency with compliance integrity.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Visibility &amp; Control Tower Dashboards</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>With our digital platform, clients receive real-time updates on every shipment, ensuring transparency in documentation, delivery timelines, and customs flow.</p>



<p>Future-Proofing Your ICT Logistics Strategy</p>



<p>As global trade policy grows more fragmented, logistics decisions must be strategic. By partnering with Truelog, telecom and datacentre firms gain:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Peace of mind around compliance<br></li>



<li>Confidence in cross-border fulfilment<br></li>



<li>Margin protection through smarter routing<br></li>
</ul>



<p>We help you keep your ICT deployments on track, even as tariffs shift.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><strong>Speak to our compliance logistics experts</strong> today to discuss how Truelog can support your U.S.-bound ICT shipments under the new rules.</p>



<p>#ICTlogistics #IORservices #CustomsCompliance #TariffMitigation #TransshipmentRisks</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/navigating-u-s-tariff-volatility-what-ict-logistics-leaders-need-to-know/">Navigating U.S. Tariff Volatility: What ICT Logistics Leaders Need to Know</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Geo-Economic Shifts Are Reshaping ICT Supply Chains in 2025</title>
		<link>https://truelog.com.sg/how-geo-economic-shifts-are-reshaping-ict-supply-chains-in-2025/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[TrueLog3]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 11:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://truelog.com.sg/?p=56847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Global ICT supply chains are facing an inflexion point. According to a July 2025 PwC report, telecom and technology firms are accelerating efforts to de-risk their logistics strategies in response to geopolitical tensions, shifting tariff regimes, and tightening export controls. The result? A transformation of how and where telecom, datacentre, and cloud hardware moves across [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/how-geo-economic-shifts-are-reshaping-ict-supply-chains-in-2025/">How Geo-Economic Shifts Are Reshaping ICT Supply Chains in 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Global ICT supply chains are facing an inflexion point. According to a July 2025 PwC report, telecom and technology firms are accelerating efforts to de-risk their logistics strategies in response to geopolitical tensions, shifting tariff regimes, and tightening export controls.</p>



<p>The result? A transformation of how and where telecom, datacentre, and cloud hardware moves across borders, and an urgent need for smarter, more compliant logistics support.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Resilience Over Efficiency</strong></h3>



<p>In place of just-in-time models and linear trade routes, ICT players are prioritising:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Friend-shoring and nearshoring</strong> to trusted regions<br></li>



<li><strong>Dual sourcing</strong> and inventory staging for hardware components<br></li>



<li><strong>Regional warehousing</strong> closer to key deployment sites<br></li>



<li><strong>Customs compliance and licensing</strong> as strategic enablers<br></li>
</ul>



<p>These trends mark a shift from lowest-cost delivery to supply chain <strong>resilience and visibility</strong>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>The Truelog Advantage: Logistics with Built-In Flexibility</strong></h3>



<p>At Truelog, we see this transformation as an opportunity to deliver strategic value. Here’s how we help our clients stay ahead:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Global IOR/EOR Services</strong><strong><br></strong>Navigate complex export and import rules across 120+ countries. Our team handles all compliance documentation, VAT, duties, and licensing on your behalf, minimising customs holds and delivery risks.<br></li>



<li><strong>Regional &amp; In-Country Warehousing</strong><strong><br></strong>With distribution hubs in Singapore, Dubai, Belgium and more, we enable flexible, SLA-driven fulfilment that aligns with your staging and deployment needs.<br></li>



<li><strong>Control Tower &amp; Digital Visibility</strong><strong><br></strong>Our unified dashboard provides real-time tracking, inventory snapshots, ticketing, and exception alerts, helping clients make informed, proactive decisions.<br></li>



<li><strong>Value-Added Services (VAS)</strong><strong><br></strong>From pre-shipment inspections to kitting and white glove delivery, we tailor logistics support to match your hardware lifecycle and deployment models.<br></li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Preparing for the New Normal in ICT Logistics</strong></h3>



<p>As geo-economic fragmentation continues, telecom and datacentre players must partner with logistics providers who:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Understand <strong>regulatory complexity</strong> across EMEA &amp; APAC<br></li>



<li>Offer <strong>compliant cross-border execution</strong><strong><br></strong></li>



<li>Provide <strong>end-to-end visibility</strong> into inventory and transit<br></li>



<li>Enable <strong>agile service models</strong> for diverse regional needs<br></li>
</ul>



<p>Truelog is that partner, bridging global strategy with local execution.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<p><strong>Ready to future-proof your ICT supply chain?</strong><strong><br></strong> Get in touch with our logistics specialists today.</p>



<p>#ICTlogistics #IORservices #TelecomSupplyChain</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/how-geo-economic-shifts-are-reshaping-ict-supply-chains-in-2025/">How Geo-Economic Shifts Are Reshaping ICT Supply Chains in 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kazakhstan’s Middle Corridor: What It Means for ICT Logistics in Eurasia</title>
		<link>https://truelog.com.sg/kazakhstans-middle-corridor-what-it-means-for-ict-logistics-in-eurasia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[TrueLog3]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 06:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://truelog.com.sg/?p=56842</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As global trade flows shift, Kazakhstan’s Middle Corridor is gaining serious traction, and that spells opportunity for ICT logistics across Eurasia. The Middle Corridor, formally known as the Trans-Caspian International Transport Route, offers a strategic overland alternative between China and Europe via Central Asia, the Caspian Sea, and the South Caucasus. With increasing investment and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/kazakhstans-middle-corridor-what-it-means-for-ict-logistics-in-eurasia/">Kazakhstan’s Middle Corridor: What It Means for ICT Logistics in Eurasia</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As global trade flows shift, Kazakhstan’s Middle Corridor is gaining serious traction, and that spells opportunity for ICT logistics across Eurasia.</p>



<p>The Middle Corridor, formally known as the Trans-Caspian International Transport Route, offers a strategic overland alternative between China and Europe via Central Asia, the Caspian Sea, and the South Caucasus. With increasing investment and political will, it&#8217;s becoming a reliable route for high-value, time-sensitive cargo, including ICT equipment.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why This Matters for ICT Logistics</strong></h3>



<p>In our industry, speed, security, and compliance are non-negotiables. With growing data centre and cloud infrastructure projects stretching across EMEA and APAC, the demand for agile logistics routes is higher than ever.</p>



<p>Here’s how the Middle Corridor supports ICT supply chains:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Reduced Lead Times: Compared to ocean freight, this corridor enables faster transit into landlocked Central Asian states like Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan, critical for time-sensitive IT rollouts.</li>



<li>Airfreight Hubs Emerging: Cities like Almaty and Astana are strengthening their role as regional airfreight and customs clearance hubs.</li>



<li>Better Diversification: With geopolitical shifts affecting other traditional trade lanes, the Middle Corridor provides an alternative for resilient ICT logistics planning.</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Truelog’s Take</strong></h3>



<p>As a specialist in ICT logistics, Truelog sees Kazakhstan’s growing connectivity as a major advantage. Whether shipping directly to data centres or staging equipment regionally, our airfreight expertise ensures seamless, compliant delivery across Eurasia.</p>



<p>With global IOR/EOR services, white glove delivery, and live tracking through our control tower, we help telecom, cloud, and infrastructure providers reach new markets faster and with confidence.</p>



<p><img decoding="async" alt="📦" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXeyTmV4y8EYIZVW-_OUb4vsvmIMjnHAR6is8T56YKQ2y2_jAm5QS18nwM5ZEGqTZq5fmO85xSsoGnB2VuhrPfuU2RxeMyZ0K4cbl6c5eDHIVbmfuHPXF2WejN2xSCrcq1XPnjvPLw?key=RQvOF-WtFwZqJwmR1HkjqQ" width="17" height="17"> Thinking about your next deployment in Central Asia? Let&#8217;s make it simple, compliant, and on time.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/kazakhstans-middle-corridor-what-it-means-for-ict-logistics-in-eurasia/">Kazakhstan’s Middle Corridor: What It Means for ICT Logistics in Eurasia</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Truelog Expands to Jordan</title>
		<link>https://truelog.com.sg/new-country-unlocked/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[TrueLog3]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 05:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Countries we serve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COmplaiance & Regulations for IT Equipment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Importing IT Equipment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IOR Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Asset Logistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Asset Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Logistics company in Singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Truelog Logistics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://truelog.com.sg/?p=56837</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Truelog is proud to announce that we are now servicing the Kingdom of Jordan, strengthening our ICT logistics network across the Middle East. Jordan’s strategic location and growing demand for ICT infrastructure make it a key market for global technology rollouts. However, navigating customs, compliance, and last-mile delivery can be challenging without the right partner. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/new-country-unlocked/">Truelog Expands to Jordan</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Truelog is proud to announce that we are now servicing the Kingdom of Jordan, strengthening our ICT logistics network across the Middle East.</p>



<p>Jordan’s strategic location and growing demand for ICT infrastructure make it a key market for global technology rollouts. However, navigating customs, compliance, and last-mile delivery can be challenging without the right partner.</p>



<p>That’s where Truelog steps in.</p>



<p>With our airfreight expertise and IATA-certified operations, we ensure fast, compliant transport of critical IT hardware into Jordan. From import licensing and VAT handling to staging, labelling, and last-mile deployment, Truelog acts as your full-service logistics partner.</p>



<p>Key capabilities in Jordan:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>IOR (Importer of Record) &amp; EOR services</strong> for compliant trade</li>



<li><strong>Airfreight logistics</strong> through trusted partners and protocols</li>



<li><strong>Staging, testing, and asset labelling</strong> for ICT rollouts</li>



<li><strong>White glove delivery &amp; remote hands</strong> for datacentre and enterprise sites</li>



<li><strong>Real-time tracking</strong> via our centralised dashboard</li>
</ul>



<p>Whether you’re deploying new infrastructure or managing spares across the region, Truelog ensures speed, security, and end-to-end visibility — now in Jordan.</p>



<p><img decoding="async" alt="📩" src="https://fonts.gstatic.com/s/e/notoemoji/16.0/1f4e9/32.png">&nbsp;Ready to simplify your ICT supply chain? Get in touch with our team today.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/new-country-unlocked/">Truelog Expands to Jordan</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ATA Carnet for Broadcasting &#038; Professional Equipment: Why Pre-Planning Is Crucial</title>
		<link>https://truelog.com.sg/ata-carnet-for-broadcasting-professional-equipment-why-pre-planning-is-crucial/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[TrueLog3]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 05:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://truelog.com.sg/?p=56808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the fast-paced world of professional broadcasting, AV, and technical services, the global movement of high-value equipment must be frictionless, compliant, and cost-effective. When Importer of Record (IOR) or temporary import/export procedures aren&#8217;t the best fit, the ATA Carnet often presents the ideal solution. But there’s one thing that makes or breaks an ATA Carnet [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/ata-carnet-for-broadcasting-professional-equipment-why-pre-planning-is-crucial/">ATA Carnet for Broadcasting &amp; Professional Equipment: Why Pre-Planning Is Crucial</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the fast-paced world of professional broadcasting, AV, and technical services, the global movement of high-value equipment must be frictionless, compliant, and cost-effective. When Importer of Record (IOR) or temporary import/export procedures aren&#8217;t the best fit, the <strong>ATA Carnet</strong> often presents the ideal solution.</p>



<p>But there’s one thing that makes or breaks an ATA Carnet shipment: <strong>pre-planning</strong>.</p>



<p><strong>What Is an ATA Carnet?</strong></p>



<p>The <strong>ATA Carnet</strong> is an international customs document that allows the <strong>duty-free and tax-free temporary import</strong> of goods into over 80 countries. Commonly used for:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Broadcast and media gear<br></li>



<li>Exhibition and demonstration kits<br></li>



<li>Surveying and calibration tools<br></li>



<li>High-value technical instruments<br></li>
</ul>



<p>The ATA Carnet allows equipment to stay in-country temporarily without incurring import duties. However, the process is <strong>paper-intensive</strong>, and each customs checkpoint may still impose <strong>strict compliance checks</strong>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why Pre-Planning ATA Shipments Is Essential</strong></h3>



<p>ATA Carnets offer a streamlined way to transport equipment globally, but only when prepared thoroughly. Key planning elements include:</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>1. Precise Equipment List</strong></h4>



<p>Customs requires a detailed list with serial numbers, accurate values, and item descriptions. Any discrepancies can lead to <strong>carnet invalidation</strong>.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>2. Route &amp; Country Eligibility</strong></h4>



<p>Not all countries accept ATA Carnets. And for those that do, entry/exit requirements may differ. Pre-routing checks are vital.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>3. Assigned Responsibilities</strong></h4>



<p>Customs stamping is mandatory at each border. Every stage needs a designated person or partner to present the carnet.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>4. Exit and Return Planning</strong></h4>



<p>Failure to close the carnet properly even if the goods return can result in <strong>penalties or full duties</strong>.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>5. Risk Management</strong></h4>



<p>Missing or damaged items under carnet may expose the shipper to full customs liability. Truelog provides <strong>end-to-end compliance oversight</strong> to mitigate this risk.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Many IOR Providers Miss the Mark on ATA</strong></h3>



<p>ATA Carnets require specific knowledge and local partnerships. Yet many IOR providers are unfamiliar with the process, advising clients to use IOR unnecessarily missing out on a faster, more compliant and cost-effective alternative.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How Truelog Delivers ATA Excellence</strong></h3>



<p>At Truelog, we take a <strong>consultative approach</strong>. Before your gear moves, we evaluate:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Cost efficiency<br></li>



<li>Transit time<br></li>



<li>Local import/export restrictions<br></li>



<li>VAT, duty, and tax exposure<br></li>



<li>Re-export obligations<br></li>
</ul>



<p>We weigh all options,<strong>IOR, temporary import, or ATA Carnet</strong> and guide you to the best fit.</p>



<p><strong>Partnership with SICC for ATA in Singapore</strong></p>



<p>As a trusted partner of the <strong>Singapore International Chamber of Commerce (SICC)</strong> the national ATA issuing body, Truelog manages carnet issuance and tracking directly, ensuring structured compliance from start to finish.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Full Lifecycle ATA Support</strong></h3>



<p>Truelog coordinates every stage of your ATA shipment with:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Accurate documentation &amp; issuance<br></li>



<li>Customs coordination for entry and exit<br></li>



<li>End-user liaison and delivery<br></li>



<li>Live tracking via our logistics control tower<br></li>
</ul>



<p>From <strong>first stamp to final return</strong>, Truelog ensures your broadcast or AV equipment moves <strong>quickly, compliantly, and risk-free</strong>.<strong>Need help with ATA Carnet planning or execution?</strong><strong><br></strong> Reach out to our logistics experts today and get a tailored compliance plan for your next shipment.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/ata-carnet-for-broadcasting-professional-equipment-why-pre-planning-is-crucial/">ATA Carnet for Broadcasting &amp; Professional Equipment: Why Pre-Planning Is Crucial</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>📢 Expansion Update: Solomon Islands 🇸🇧</title>
		<link>https://truelog.com.sg/%f0%9f%93%a2-expansion-update-solomon-islands-%f0%9f%87%b8%f0%9f%87%a7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[TrueLog3]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 11:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://truelog.com.sg/?p=56741</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that the Solomon Islands comprises of 992 islands of which only 147 are inhabited! With limited port infrastructure, logistics here require precision. Add strict import rules, advance manifests and full duty payment, and the need for a reliable IOR/EOR partner becomes clear. Truelog ensures compliant freight routing, climate-protected packaging, and regional warehousing [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/%f0%9f%93%a2-expansion-update-solomon-islands-%f0%9f%87%b8%f0%9f%87%a7/">📢 Expansion Update: Solomon Islands 🇸🇧</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Did you know that the Solomon Islands comprises of 992 islands of which only 147 are inhabited!</p>



<p>With limited port infrastructure, logistics here require precision. Add strict import rules, advance manifests and full duty payment, and the need for a reliable IOR/EOR partner becomes clear.</p>



<p>Truelog ensures compliant freight routing, climate-protected packaging, and regional warehousing to keep your ICT deployments on track.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/%f0%9f%93%a2-expansion-update-solomon-islands-%f0%9f%87%b8%f0%9f%87%a7/">📢 Expansion Update: Solomon Islands 🇸🇧</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>DP World’s $2.5B Bet on UAE Logistics – What It Means for ICT Deployments</title>
		<link>https://truelog.com.sg/dp-worlds-2-5b-bet-on-uae-logistics-what-it-means-for-ict-deployments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[TrueLog3]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 10:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://truelog.com.sg/?p=56739</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>DP World’s commitment to invest $2.5 billion in logistics infrastructure underlines the UAE’s growing significance as a global supply chain hub. This initiative includes expanding ports, building new corridors, and enhancing multimodal capabilities. For ICT providers deploying equipment across MEA, this represents a major enabler. Truelog’s Dubai operations are already aligned with this vision, offering: [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/dp-worlds-2-5b-bet-on-uae-logistics-what-it-means-for-ict-deployments/">DP World’s $2.5B Bet on UAE Logistics – What It Means for ICT Deployments</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size">DP World’s commitment to invest $2.5 billion in logistics infrastructure underlines the UAE’s growing significance as a global supply chain hub. This initiative includes expanding ports, building new corridors, and enhancing multimodal capabilities.</h3>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size">For ICT providers deploying equipment across MEA, this represents a major enabler. Truelog’s Dubai operations are already aligned with this vision, offering:</h3>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li class="has-medium-font-size">Regional warehousing with full visibility</li>



<li class="has-medium-font-size">IOR/EOR services compliant with UAE regulations</li>



<li class="has-medium-font-size">Last-mile delivery with white glove and rack &amp; stack</li>



<li class="has-medium-font-size">Reverse logistics and certified ITAD support</li>



<li class="has-medium-font-size">24/7 control tower for real-time updates</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size">Our centralised logistics model, backed by a regional footprint and deep customs expertise, helps clients cut deployment time, ensure compliance, and maintain SLA integrity across complex MEA markets.</h3>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size">DP World’s investment accelerates infrastructure, Truelog makes it operational.</h3>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"></h3>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/dp-worlds-2-5b-bet-on-uae-logistics-what-it-means-for-ict-deployments/">DP World’s $2.5B Bet on UAE Logistics – What It Means for ICT Deployments</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>India’s Logistics Infrastructure, Hosur’s Emerging ICT Corridor</title>
		<link>https://truelog.com.sg/indias-logistics-infrastructure-hosurs-emerging-ict-corridor/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[TrueLog3]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 10:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://truelog.com.sg/?p=56737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Panattoni’s announcement of a €100 million investment to build a Grade-A industrial and logistics park in Hosur, Tamil Nadu, is a strategic move. As a key link between Bengaluru and Chennai, Hosur is poised to become South India’s next logistics and manufacturing hub. Truelog India, based in Chennai, is uniquely positioned to support ICT companies [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/indias-logistics-infrastructure-hosurs-emerging-ict-corridor/">India’s Logistics Infrastructure, Hosur’s Emerging ICT Corridor</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size">Panattoni’s announcement of a €100 million investment to build a Grade-A industrial and logistics park in Hosur, Tamil Nadu, is a strategic move. As a key link between Bengaluru and Chennai, Hosur is poised to become South India’s next logistics and manufacturing hub.</h3>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size">Truelog India, based in Chennai, is uniquely positioned to support ICT companies taking advantage of this emerging corridor. Our logistics offerings in India are designed around compliance, scalability, and local expertise. We provide:</h3>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li class="has-medium-font-size">IOR/EOR services tailored for ICT equipment imports and exports</li>



<li class="has-medium-font-size">Regional warehousing with ITAM &amp; ITAD capabilities</li>



<li class="has-medium-font-size">Asset tagging, data wiping, and certified disposal (EU/US standards)</li>



<li class="has-medium-font-size">Live tracking and SLA management via our central dashboard</li>



<li class="has-medium-font-size">Support for local and cross-border B2B2C operations</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size">The strategic value of Hosur lies in its location, infrastructure, and government support. With Truelog’s strong presence and a “glocal” model, we empower global clients to operate seamlessly across India.</h3>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"></h3>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/indias-logistics-infrastructure-hosurs-emerging-ict-corridor/">India’s Logistics Infrastructure, Hosur’s Emerging ICT Corridor</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK-EU Trade Reset – A New Era for ICT Logistics</title>
		<link>https://truelog.com.sg/uk-eu-trade-reset-a-new-era-for-ict-logistics/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[TrueLog3]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 10:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://truelog.com.sg/?p=56735</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The recent UK-EU trade agreement, announced on 19 May 2025, marks a significant turning point for cross-border logistics, particularly within the ICT sector. This deal introduces streamlined customs procedures, reduced paperwork, and improved regulatory alignment, facilitating smoother movement of goods between the UK and EU. Key Highlights of the Agreement: Implications for ICT Logistics: For [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/uk-eu-trade-reset-a-new-era-for-ict-logistics/">UK-EU Trade Reset – A New Era for ICT Logistics</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size">The recent UK-EU trade agreement, announced on 19 May 2025, marks a significant turning point for cross-border logistics, particularly within the ICT sector. This deal introduces streamlined customs procedures, reduced paperwork, and improved regulatory alignment, facilitating smoother movement of goods between the UK and EU.</h3>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size"><strong>Key Highlights of the Agreement:</strong></h3>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Simplified Customs Procedures:</strong> The agreement reduces bureaucratic hurdles, allowing for more efficient processing of ICT equipment across borders.<br></li>



<li class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Regulatory Alignment:</strong> Enhanced cooperation on standards ensures that ICT products meet both UK and EU requirements, minimizing delays caused by compliance issues.<br></li>



<li class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Improved Data Flows:</strong> The deal supports better data sharing between customs authorities, aiding in the swift clearance of goods.<br></li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size"><strong>Implications for ICT Logistics:</strong></h3>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size">For companies operating within the ICT supply chain, these developments offer several advantages:</h3>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Faster Transit Times:</strong> Reduced customs checks and aligned regulations mean that ICT components and equipment can move more swiftly between the UK and EU, crucial for time-sensitive deployments.<br></li>



<li class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Cost Savings:</strong> Streamlined procedures lower administrative costs associated with cross-border trade, allowing for more competitive pricing and budgeting.<br></li>



<li class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Enhanced Reliability:</strong> With fewer regulatory surprises and delays, supply chains become more predictable, improving planning and customer satisfaction.<br></li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size"><strong>Truelog’s Role in the New Trade Landscape:</strong></h3>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size">At Truelog, we are poised to help our clients navigate and capitalize on these changes:</h3>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Expertise in IOR/EOR Services:</strong> Our deep understanding of both UK and EU import/export regulations ensures compliance and efficiency in cross-border transactions.<br></li>



<li class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Advanced Digital Tools:</strong> Our unified logistics dashboard provides real-time tracking and management of shipments, enhancing visibility and control.<br></li>



<li class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Strategic Warehousing:</strong> With facilities in key locations, we offer staging, kitting, and last-mile delivery services tailored to the ICT sector’s needs.<br></li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size"><strong>Conclusion:</strong></h3>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading has-medium-font-size">The UK-EU trade agreement opens new avenues for streamlined ICT logistics. By leveraging Truelog’s expertise and infrastructure, businesses can ensure their supply chains are agile, compliant, and ready to meet the demands of a rapidly evolving market.</h3>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://truelog.com.sg/uk-eu-trade-reset-a-new-era-for-ict-logistics/">UK-EU Trade Reset – A New Era for ICT Logistics</a> appeared first on <a href="https://truelog.com.sg">Truelog</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
